#### FULL STACK DEVELOPER

# amy-braswell.github.io/portfolio-site

# Amy Braswell.

# **Profile**

I am a mid-career professional seeking a full stack development position. I enjoy transforming code into an elegant experience for the end-user while balancing visual concerns with technical requirements. I am a lifelong learner with 15+ years of expertise in client services, design, mentoring, production work and project delivery.

+1 773 206 5872



amy@amybraswell.com



Chicago, IL 60607



# Skills

### Frontend

- JavaScript
- React
- Redux
- Enzyme
- jQuery
- HTML5
- CSS3
- Photoshop
- · Responsive Design
- · Web Accessibility

### Backend

- · Node.js
- MongoDB
- · Mocha & Chai
- Passport
- REST APIs 3

### Dev Tools

- Git
- · GitHub
- · Chrome Dev Tools
- Heroku
- Travis CI
- Photoshop
- · Responsive Design
- Web Accessibility

# Education

## MASTERS OF FINE ARTS

Photography
Columbia College Chicago
(3.74 / 4.00 GPA)

## NURSING PREREQUISITES

Math & Sciences (40 credits)
City Colleges of Chicago
(3.90 / 4.00 GPA)

# Volunteer

GiveCamp Memphis
GiveCamp.org
2020

# **Projects**

#### FIND A NATIONAL PARK

Find a Park | See My Code

- Developed an app that returns the National Parks in a state the user specifies.
- Designed the user interface for mobile and browser responsiveness.
- · Skills HTML, CSS, jQuery, Fetch

# CAMERA OPERATIONS QUIZ APP

Take the Quiz | See My Code

- Developed a guiz app to test the user's understanding of camera controls.
- Designed the user interface for mobile and browser responsiveness.
- · Skills HTML, CSS, jQuery

# Work Experience

#### BLOC - FULL STACK DEVELOPMENT PROGRAM | 2019 - PRESENT

- Learned industry best practices and practical software development standards with a focus on HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, and React.
- Created and deployed mobile-first applications while learning new languages and frameworks by collaborating several hours every week with a senior web developer.

## OWNER / OPERATOR - STUDIO PHOTOGRAPHER

AMY BRASWELL PHOTOGRAPHY | 2001 - PRESENT

- Planned and prepared for all studio shoots.
- Photographed high-quality imagery for in-store, print and digital distribution.
- Collaborated with other team members to provide on-brand visuals while meeting aggressive timelines.
- Remained composed and calm in very fast-paced, stressful and constantly changing environments to provide optimal desired results.
- Developed reputation as an industry-expert through on-going research of industry trends, new techniques, and software updates.

## ADJUNCT FACULTY MEMBER

PHOTOGRAPHY DEPT - COLUMBIA COLLEGE CHICAGO | 2000 - 2016

- Developed and implemented lesson plans designed to teach camera operations, tethered shooting and studio lighting.
- Engaged students by encouraging participation in class and sharing on the subject under discussion.
- Proactively mentored students in the development and achievement of their professional goals.
- Was 1 of 2 adjunct faculty members (out of 60) selected by the department to advise the full-time faculty on best practices in software workflow from an industry perspective as the department developed their digital curriculum for the core foundational classes.